San Francisco, CA (818) 521- 2467 VrturoPerez@gmail.com

# **Arturo Perez**

github.com/Vrturo linkedin.com/in/Vrturo Vrturo.io

## **LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES**

Proficient: Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, Node.js, Express, Jade, Git, MySQL, ActiveRecord, Heroku,

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Exposure: ReactJS, Socket.IO, FireBase, MongoDB, TDD(RSpec, Jasmine, Capybara), LESS

## RECENT PROJECTS

### TheHufts | Front End Engineer | https://thehufts.herokuapp.com

Web app that's used as a stock training platform, that allows you to upload and backtest your own algorithms.

- Designed the navigation bar, custom forms, and UI/UX of entire app using Bootstrap and custom CSS/JS.
- Applied the HighCharts API, a Dashboard/Admin type view is given, displaying given data onto the charts.
- Leveraged CodeMirror API to display a text editor for users to create algorithms to manipulate stock data.
- Migrated to EJS to embed JS logic in the view to determine what to display based on specific criteria.

## B.A.C.E. | Full-Stack Engineer | https://bacestimator.herokuapp.com

Platform estimates a user's B.A.C. based on their weight, gender, time drinking, and ozs of alcohol drank.

- Created a friendly user experience with objects from the DOM moving on clicks, using Javascript/jQuery.
- Utilized Uber's API and Sinatra to give a user the option to Sign In/Sign Up with their Uber Account.
- Engineered an algorithm that return a user's B.A.C. with the parameters that are filled in from a form.
- Wrote functional tests in a TDD environment to validate changes in the database and HTTP responses.

## The Game| Back End Engineer | https://github.com/cpbasham/TheGame-0.2

'The Game' is an online 2D multiplayer side-scrolling shooting game.

- Implemented agile development methodologies with Object-Orientation and used MVC design structure.
- Formalized Node.js with MongoDB to hold new users, on-going/new game rooms, and user messages.
- Incorporated Socket.IO into client-side architecture with Express.JS/Node allowing real time game play.

#### CalTrain Departures | Full-Stack Engineer | https://sfdeparturetimes.herokuapp.com/

A service for commuters that gives real-time departure times for the San Francisco Caltrain.

- Used HTML5 Geolocation API to gather user's coordinates and Google Maps API to display it on a map.
- Accessed the 511 transit API to retrieve the XML data that contains the Caltrain departure times.
- Developed an automated user experience by parsing a huge XML data object to display all possibilities.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### Web Developer Mentor | Dev BootCamp, San Francisco, CA

2015 - Current

- Troubleshoot errors with students by walking through the underlying logic and determining edge cases.
- Helped students on topics such as OOP best practices, ruby fundamentals, and algorithmic problem solving.

#### Sales and Marketing Affiliate | Vemma, Riverside, CA

2013 - 2015

- Developed successful sales and marketing strategies which exceeded the revenue forecast every quarter.
- Mentored new sales affiliates to develop their skills in order to increase confidence and productivity.
- Established exceptional ability to achieve client marketing goals while supervising others simultaneously.
- Hosted and gave talks to over 200+ people at company networking events and training programs.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Dev BootCamp,** *Software Engineering Immersive* **Riverside College**, *Computer Science* 

2015 - 2015